# david@davidwatson.org 🚨 🖹 🖶

### **Objective**

Help small teams deliver reliable, usable, and valuable software using incremental, reflective, and minimal process.

### Summary

Helped design, develop, and deploy software across desktop, internet, and mobile platforms.

#### **Skills**

### Operating Systems & Programming Languages

Productive working on Linux (Unix-like), MacOS (BSD), and Windows (WSL2) since they have similar GUI and CLI.

Since 2005, wrote Python daily, C++ or Ruby occasionally. Prior to 2005 wrote C++ daily, Python or Ruby occasionally.

#### Containers & Virtual Machines

Used Docker since 2015, Kubernetes since 2017, and VMWare since 2000.

#### Markup & Markdown

Prefer markup, markdown, or plain text for a variety of technical documentation, including this resume.

#### **Databases & Methods**

Used PostgreSQL since 2008 for its support for relational and schemaless data plus numerous extensions.

Tailored agile based on a synthesis of research from Alistair Cockburn, Allen Holub, and Bonnitta Roy.

#### **Experience**

Software Engineering Specialist Caterpillar 2018-2020, 2021

- Built, reviewed and profiled C++ code on Linux from Intel x86 to ARM for Autonomy Group
- Guided company-wide directives on docker container usage for build engineering and CI/CD on Azure

# Member of Technical Staff Carnegie Mellon University 2020

- · Contributed to Emerging Technology Center within Software Engineering Institute
- · Worked on HPC, MLOps, and HCI in concert with National Robotics Engineering Center

### Software Developer Realpage 2016 - 2018

- Led weekly retrospectives to improve cadence, velocity, and teamwork
- Implemented crawler data pipeline using Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, and Kubernetes/AWS

### VP Product Development Wellbridge Health 2015 - 2016

- Led development team through HIPAA-compliant MVP with SPA UX design from MAYA
- Implemented REST API using Python/Django, DRF and PostgreSQL serving EmberJS SPA on Aptible

### VP Engineering Hire an Esquire 2014

- Led engineering team to redesign and simplify MVP
- · Refactored Python, Django, and PostgreSQL stack with vanilla Django and Bootstrap frontend

# Software Developer Forever 2013 - 2014

- Wrote Python, Flask, MongoDB proof-of-concept demonstrating photo sharing and storage on Heroku
- Productionized design using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS

## Software Engineer BrainStorm 2011 - 2012

- · Contributed python, postgreSQL code to internal systems supporting daily operations
- Designed and implemented conversational text systems (like twilio) and REST interfaces in python

#### Software Development Manager Wellspring 2010 - 2011

- Led devops from legacy data center to SaaS VMWare deployment
- Built CI/CD systems using Capistrano (Ruby), Mechanize (Python), and Selenium

### Project Engineer Qinetiq 2008-2009

- Visualized XML sonar data in python, consumed by C++ GUI application on Windows
- Ported Microsoft C#.net Windows GUI to C++/Qt/Linux for OCU deployment

### UI Software Engineer Nomos 2006 - 2007

- Contributed C++ QA tests and code reviews to CORVUS FDA-regulated radiation oncology product
- Prototyped wireframes and rendered storyboards in C++/Qt for adaptive 4D treatment planning

#### Software Design Engineer MAYA Design 2004 - 2006

- · Built REST backends in python emitting JSON for consumption by proprietary AJAX frontends
- Demoed GUI floorplan wireless lighting designer in C#/Windows for Lutron 1 week from sketch

#### Co-Founder Cobind 2003 - 2004

- Partnered on ideation, vision, and execution of custom Linux Tools startup
- Received wide press acclaim around custom Linux products after winning Idea Foundry Fellowship

#### Software Engineer MSA 2000-2003

- · Contributed code, data, and deployment before and after startup acquisition
- Implemented backend product import systems providing Excel VBA API from spreadsheet to database

# Member of Technical Staff CA 1995-2000

- Built C++ GUI for Legent (Automation Point) and Platinum (Raveler), before acquisition by CA
- Wrote C++ code for CA-Unicenter products after CA acquisition

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Science Duquesne University 1991